<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tmz on Top Secret Labs - Richard Sumilang </title>
    <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://richardsumilang.com/tags/tmz/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
    
    <updated>Sun, 96 Aug 220900 09:09:09 PST</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>TMZ Mobile Website</title>
      <link>http://richardsumilang.com/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 96 Aug 220900 09:09:09 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>http://richardsumilang.com/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It has been an exciting journey from start to finish. As the head developer of
the mobile website for one of the world&amp;rsquo;s biggest blog sites, I&amp;rsquo;m pleased to
announce &lt;em&gt;Version 2&lt;/em&gt; of TMZ! Take a look at all the new features. I think you
will like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;disclaimer:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The views and opinions shared in this article are those of the author&amp;rsquo;s (Richard
Sumilang) and do not necessarily reflect TMZ, Telepictures, Warner Bros and any
staff member or affiliate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-role:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;My role&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a full time developer at TMZ. I work on TMZ products such as the desktop
site and internal applications. My current focus is bringing the technologies up
to date with modern standards while enhancing the user experience on the mobile
website. In other words, creating a brand new product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-s-more-than-just-a-pretty-face:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s more than just a pretty face&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new site provides a new fun and modern interface to interact with TMZ&amp;rsquo;s
content. It borrows designs from our native mobile applications so you feel at
home; but they have been optimized for the mobile web browsing experience. It&amp;rsquo;s
lighter, faster, and full of new features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inside has been built from the ground up. While I would like to write a
series of articles detailing the various technologies I chose to build the
application, I will say ECMAScript 6 proved itself suitable as the front-end
language and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to continue upgrading the application to ECMAScript 7,
ECMAScript 8, and so fourth as JavaScript continues to gain sanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;show-me-the-features:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Show me the features!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you will notice is a fresh skin. It&amp;rsquo;s clean, intuitive, and
brings the familiarity you would expect out of a mobile website. The large
images help you find the content you are looking for while continuing to load
more articles into the feed as you scroll, keeping your browsing experience
smooth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/homepage.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;navigation-menu:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Navigation Menu&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the top left we have a menu button that pulls out a panel to allow navigation
to each section of the site. Starting from the top, you can find the &amp;ldquo;Got a tip?&amp;rdquo;
button where you can submit tips directly to TMZ. Following that we have each of
our site sections in big easily clickable buttons. Below that is a &amp;ldquo;Mobile
Alerts&amp;rdquo; button allowing you to register and receive mobile alerts sent directly
to your phone. The &amp;ldquo;TV Listings&amp;rdquo; displays TMZ show listings for your area. Or if
you&amp;rsquo;re feeling like going on a tour then you can click the &amp;ldquo;TMZ Celebrity Tour&amp;rdquo;
and reserve a spot on the bus and tour hollywood. The &amp;ldquo;Login / Register&amp;rdquo; button
signs you into TMZ, allowing you to add your own comments to articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/nav-menu.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;got-a-tip:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Got A Tip?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calling TMZ directly is still an option by clicking the &amp;ldquo;Give us a call&amp;rdquo; button.
The new section now supports sending TMZ a direct email via a web form with the
ability to upload files from your phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/got-a-tip.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;news:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;News&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The news contains tabs to help you sort the content in your preferred order. For
example, this feed defaults to the &lt;strong&gt;Latest&lt;/strong&gt; articles and provides you the
options of sorting by most &lt;strong&gt;Popular&lt;/strong&gt; and the most &lt;strong&gt;Commented&lt;/strong&gt; trending
results. The &lt;strong&gt;Popular&lt;/strong&gt; tab labels each article with a number for it&amp;rsquo;s
popularity. The &lt;strong&gt;Commented&lt;/strong&gt; section similarly labels each article with the
number of comments per article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/news-feed.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;article-page:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Article Page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking an article thumbnail brings you to a beautiful view of the article that
is easy to read. The cover is either an image, video, or gallery. You can tell
what the media type is because there is either a large play button for video or
gallery icon for galleries. You can click the primary media in the cover to load
the media right away or you can scroll down the article. As you scroll you will
notice buttons for sharing an article on your social networks and the comment
count next to the article details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the article details there can be links to more related galleries, videos,
images, polls, and a number of other items (depending on what the content writer
chose to include).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking on the comment bubble next to the article details, or the large comment
count below the article will show load all the comments. You may log in here
using one of many social network authentications (Facebook, Twitter, Gmail, etc)
to share your thoughts. If you are already logged into the mobile website with
your TMZ account then you can comment immediately. Closing the comment page will
bring you back to the article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below you will find other related articles that you may find interesting. The
want more section will display buttons to bios of celebrities mentioned in the
article and buttons to article categories that you also may find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end you will see a link to the next article from the feed you came from.
If you did not land on the article page coming from a feed then you will not see
this feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/article-page.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;videos:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Videos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featuring &lt;em&gt;Latest Videos&lt;/em&gt; by default, TMZ now provides access to videos by
&lt;em&gt;Category&lt;/em&gt;. Each video also has it&amp;rsquo;s own page where you can share the current
video with your social networks and find other related videos that you might be
interested in watching next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/video-latest.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;photos:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Photos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like all the other feeds, bigger images and easier scrolling. The takeaway from
this section is the new thumbnail galleries that you can load by clicking on any
photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the gallery, we use larger images to take up the whole viewport of your phone
to provide a richer experience. You can swipe your thumb on a photo to easily
navigate in the direction you want to go. There are also new sharing features
per photo and more gallery suggestions when reaching the end. I think you&amp;rsquo;ll
like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/photo-galleries.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sports:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Sports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This feed is similar to the latest news feed but focuses on the &lt;em&gt;Sports&lt;/em&gt;
category. You can also find sports articles while browsing other article feeds.
You will be able to easily identify a sports article by the green swipe on the
article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/tmz-sports.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;celebs:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Celebs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the most trending celebrity by navigating to this feed section. This section
defaults to the most &lt;strong&gt;Trending&lt;/strong&gt; celebrities and you can click on the &lt;strong&gt;All&lt;/strong&gt;
tab to find a specific celebrity quicker. The &lt;strong&gt;All&lt;/strong&gt; section loads smaller
thumbnails for faster scrolling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/celebs.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;celebrity-bio:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Celebrity Bio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clicking on a celebrity will load up a detailed biography page where you can
find more information about a celebrity. Starting from the top, you can share the
celebrity information with your social network, read their bio, find photo
galleries, videos, and/or articles featuring the current celebrity bio you are
reading. We also show related celebrities that you may be interested in
reading about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/celeb-bio.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shows:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Shows&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Broken up into three sections, TMZ, TMZ Live, and TMZ Sports. You can come to
this section and watch live streaming (for TMZ Live), full episodes, and clips
for any of your favorite shows on your mobile device. You may also use the
button on the bottom of the page to find local TV listings for your area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/shows.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;search:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Search&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t find what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for? Try out the new search feature. It uses an
updated backend service to provide you more accurate results than before. From
the search page you will be able to find celebrities, articles, videos, and
galleries. Celebrities will be listed first and the other page types will be
mixed in the results. You can identify each page type by the icons on the
results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/search-dave.gif&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;try-it-out-for-yourself:109091b091afade9d62503f31848530f&#34;&gt;Try it out for yourself!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This application is now live. You can access it on your mobile device by going to
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tmz.com&#34;&gt;http://www.tmz.com&lt;/a&gt; or directly to &lt;a href=&#34;http://m.tmz.com&#34;&gt;http://m.tmz.com&lt;/a&gt;. This mobile website is a
huge improvement over the previous implementation and I&amp;rsquo;m proud to have my name
stamped on the face of it. Many thanks to my awesome team for help making this
possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/etc/work/tmz/tmz-mobile-web-version-2/tmz-logo.png&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First day at TMZ</title>
      <link>http://richardsumilang.com/etc/first-day-at-tmz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 46 Aug 10400 04:04:04 PST</pubDate>
      <author>Richard Sumilang</author>
      <guid>http://richardsumilang.com/etc/first-day-at-tmz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks day 1 of my journey at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tmz.com/&#34; title=&#34;Thirty Mile Zone&#34;&gt;TMZ&lt;/a&gt;. There is an exciting energy in
this environment. The first thing you notice is an open workspace where there is
action going on every minute. (You probably already know that if you&amp;rsquo;ve watched
the show before.) The technology is also very impressive. The team no doubt
consists of nothing but A+ players. How else would TMZ have gotten to be so big
in a short amount of time? I&amp;rsquo;m excited to bring my skills to the team and to see
what the future has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://richardsumilang.com/images/me/tmz.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;In the news room&#34; class=&#34;center&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
